A Guide to the Edward Ingraham Papers 1980.0035
Archives and Special Collections at the Thomas J. Dodd Research Center, University of Connecticut Library
Edward Ingraham Papers
1787-1971
Archives and Special Collections at the Thomas J. Dodd Research Center, University of Connecticut Library
1980.0035
12 Linear Feet
Edward Ingraham was born in Bristol, Connecticut. He was the great-grandson of Elias Ingraham. Mr. Ingraham was the president of the E. Ingraham Company from 1927- 1954. He died in 1972 at the age of 85.
Access
The collection is open and available for research.
Acquisition Information
In January 1980 these papers were donated by Yale University Library to the University of Connecticut Libraries, and placed in Historical Manuscripts and Archives (now Archives & Special Collections), located in the Dodd Research Center.
Arrangement
Series I: Correspondence (undated, 1931-1959) contains a variety of materials, including correspondence, minutes of meetings' memoranda, and other types of papers. This series constitutes the core collection of Edward Ingraham Papers, initially donated to Yale University and arranged chronologically. Most of these papers relate to his 27-year career as president of E. Ingraham Company. In addition to official papers, the collection includes correspondence relating to his service as president of the Clock Manufacturers Association of America, the Manufacturers Association of Connecticut, the American Clock and Watch Museum in Bristol, as well as the Bristol Boys Association, also as director of the International Silver Company, the Bristol Brass Corporation, Associated Spring Cooperation of Bristol, and the Bristol Bank and Trust Company; and as chairman for Connecticut of the Wooden Crusade for the restoration of war-stricken churches in Germany and as well as an active committee member for the Connecticut Junior Republic, the Bristol Library, and the Yale University Class of 1910.
The papers are of historical, economic and social interest in their documentation of the development of the American clock and watch industry, the establishment of the American Clock and Watch museum, the effect of the Swiss Tariff issue on the American clock industry and on U.S. governmental and economic policies. Included are records dealing with various War Board Committees established by the federal government to formulate industrial policies for the course of the national defense. Labor History is documented in records of union company arbitration decisions, legal evaluations of their relevance to similar labor- management situations at the E. Ingraham Company, and extensive minutes of union-company meetings. The minutes, recorded by company lawyers, contain accounts of union management disputes, detailed reports of plant operations both technical and social, job descriptions, and memoranda on the attitudes and reactions of employee toward union and management. Special topics in business history include problems of the clock industry in the time of war, the role of the clock business in defense, technological and social problems of reconversion from war to peacetime production, and geographical can managerial problems of plant expansion. The role and responsibilities of the business administrator in civic and state affairs is documented by correspondence concerned with Mr. Ingraham's professional and social relationships with man of the clock and other vital industries.
In the area of Connecticut State and local history, the papers describe the E. Ingraham Company as a family business of essential importance to the people of Bristol, for whom the company was a major source of employment. The family dedication to the company is clearly seen in the professional relationship of Dudley and Edward Ingraham. The series also includes correspondence of special not between Mr. Ingraham and John Joseph Murphy, a graduate student of economics at Yale. Mr. Murphy used the E. Ingraham Company papers as the basis of a doctoral dissertation completed in 1961. His dissertation is entitled, The Establishment of the American Clock- Making Industry.
Series II: Select Correspondence (undated, 1841-1971) contains correspondence donated to Yale at a later date, which was arranged separately by name of correspondent. These individuals include family members, relatives, close friends, and others.
Series III: Personal Correspondence (undated, 1883-1964) also contains correspondence not included in the original collection of Edward Ingraham Papers. Most of the items in this series pre-date Series I. They include family letters, postcards from extensive travels by relatives and friends, and related materials, arranged chronologically.
Series IV: Writings (undated, 1940-1963) consists of Edward Ingraham's unpublished articles, speeches, reminiscences, research notes, and other writings. Major topics include the history of theE. Ingraham Company, clock-making, the impact of WWII on business, Ingraham family genealogy, personal reminiscences and autobiography, and related concerns.
Series V: Subject Files (undated, 1787-1969) contains a variety of materials relating to E. Ingraham activities and Edward Ingraham's personal interests. Files are arranged alphabetically by topic.
Biography
Edward Ingraham was born 20 December 1887, and raised in Bristol, CT. He was the great-grandson of Elias Ingraham, an entrepreneur in early American clock- making and the founder of the E. Ingraham Company, a manufacturer of clocks and non-jeweled watches. After graduating from Yale in 1910, he began his long association with the E. Ingraham Company. From 1927 - 1954, he served as president of the company.
In 1918, Mr. Ingraham married Alice Patti Pease, a French teacher in the Bristol High School. They had five children, four daughters (Alice, Grace, Ellen, and Faith), and a son, William Shurtleff Ingraham. After Mrs. Ingraham's death, Mr. Ingraham married Ethel Leishman Beach, a trust officer at the Bristol Bank and Trust Company on January 16, 1952. Ethel Ingraham was born 3 January 1895 in Bristol, the daughter of John and Agnes Turnbull Leishman.
Edward Ingraham possessed a deep concern for the tradition and craft of clock-making, evidenced by his active support for the establishment of a clock and watch museum, and his great sense of personal pride in the role of the Ingraham family in the industry's historical and technical history. He viewed the manufacture of time mechanisms as an activity vital to the security of the American people, especially in periods of national emergency.
Edward Ingraham died in 1972 at the age of 85. Ethel L. Ingraham died in 1980.
Scope and Content
The Edward Ingraham Papers (1787 - 1971, bulk 1931-1959) comprise the personal and business papers of Edward Ingraham (1887- 1972), president of E. Ingraham Company, a Bristol, Connecticut, manufacturer of clocks and watches. The papers include personal and business correspondence, a small quantity of E. Ingraham Company records, materials concerning the National Association of Clock and Watch Manufacturers, his writings about Connecticut clock- making, Ingraham family genealogy, personal reminiscences, and other topics.
Connecticut (state); Clock and watch industry; Clocks and watches; Administrative records; Correspondence; E. Ingraham Company; Ingraham
- Series I: Correspondence, undated, 1931-1959
  - 1931 January - 1937 December (Box 1:, Folder 1)
  - 1938 January 1 - 12 (Box 1:, Folder 2)
  - 1938 January 13 - 18 (Box 1:, Folder 3)
  - 1938 January 19 - 31 (Box 1:, Folder 4)
  - 1938 February 1 - 11 (Box 1:, Folder 5)
  - 1938 February 12 - 18 (Box 1:, Folder 6)
  - 1938 February 19 - 24 (Box 1:, Folder 7)
  - 1938 February 25 - 28 (Box 1:, Folder 8)
  - 1938 March 1 - 8 (Box 1:, Folder 9)
  - 1938 March 9 - 19 (Box 1:, Folder 10)
  - 1938 March 20 - 25 (Box 1:, Folder 11)
  - 1938 March 26 - 31 (Box 1:, Folder 12)
  - 1938 April 1 - 9 (Box 1:, Folder 13)
  - 1938 April 10 - 18 (Box 1:, Folder 14)
  - 1938 April 19 - 25 (Box 1:, Folder 15)
  - 1938 April 26 - 30 (Box 1:, Folder 16)
  - 1938 May 1 - 10 (Box 1:, Folder 17)
  - 1938 May 11 - 13 (Box 1:, Folder 18)
  - 1938 May 14 - 20 (Box 1:, Folder 19)
  - 1938 May 21 - 31 (Box 1:, Folder 20)
  - 1938 June 1 - 10 (Box 1:, Folder 21)
  - 1938 June 11 - 22 (Box 2:, Folder 22)
  - 1938 June 23 - 30 (Box 2:, Folder 23)
  - 1938 July 1 - 13 (Box 2:, Folder 24)
  - 1938 July 14 - 22 (Box 2:, Folder 25)
  - 1938 July 23 - 31 (Box 2:, Folder 26)
  - 1938 August 1 - 5 (Box 2:, Folder 27)
  - 1938 August 6 - 19 (Box 2:, Folder 28)
  - 1938 August 20 - 24 (Box 2:, Folder 29)
  - 1938 August 25 - 31 (Box 2:, Folder 30)
  - 1938 September 1 - 15 (Box 2:, Folder 31)
  - 1938 September 16 - 23 (Box 2:, Folder 32)
  - 1938 September 24 - 30 (Box 2:, Folder 33)
  - 1938 October 1 - 7 (Box 2:, Folder 34)
  - 1938 October 8 - 13 (Box 2:, Folder 35)
  - 1938 October 14 - 20 (Box 2:, Folder 36)
  - 1938 October 21 - 31 (Box 2:, Folder 37)
  - 1938 November 1 - 7 (Box 2:, Folder 38)
  - 1938 November 8 - 17 (Box 2:, Folder 39)
  - 1938 November 18 - 28 (Box 2:, Folder 40)
  - 1938 November 29 - 30 (Box 2:, Folder 41)
  - 1938 December 1 - 8 (Box 2:, Folder 42)
  - 1938 December 9 - 16 (Box 3:, Folder 43)
  - 1938 December 17 - 23 (Box 3:, Folder 44)
  - 1938 December 24 - 31 (Box 3:, Folder 45)
  - 1939 January - June (Box 3:, Folder 46)
  - 1939 July - December (Box 3:, Folder 47)
  - 1940 January (Box 3:, Folder 48)
  - 1940 February - July (Box 3:, Folder 49)
  - 1940 August - September (Box 3:, Folder 50)
  - 1940 October - December (Box 3:, Folder 51)
  - 1941 January - February (Box 3:, Folder 52)
  - 1941 March (Box 3:, Folder 53)
  - 1941 April 1 - 8 (Box 3:, Folder 54)
  - 1941 April 9 - 30 (Box 3:, Folder 55)
  - 1941 May 1 - 12 (Box 3:, Folder 56)
  - 1941 May 13 - 19 (Box 3:, Folder 57)
  - 1941 May 20 - June (Box 3:, Folder 58)
  - 1941 July - September (Box 3:, Folder 59)
  - 1941 October - December (Box 3:, Folder 60)
  - 1942 January - February (Box 3:, Folder 61)
  - 1942 March - May (Box 3:, Folder 62)
  - 1942 June 1 - 6 (Box 3:, Folder 63)
  - 1942 June 7 - 10 (Box 4:, Folder 64)
  - 1942 June 11 - 30 (Box 4:, Folder 65)
  - 1942 July 1 - 14 (Box 4:, Folder 66)
  - 1942 July 15 - 31 (Box 4:, Folder 67)
  - 1942 August - September 1 (Box 4:, Folder 68)
  - 1942 September 2 - December (Box 4:, Folder 69)
  - 1943 January 1 - 20 (Box 4:, Folder 70)
  - 1943 January 21 - 31 (Box 4:, Folder 71)
  - 1943 February 1 - 28 (Box 4:, Folder 72)
  - 1943 March - May (Box 4:, Folder 73)
  - 1943 June 1 - 11 (Box 4:, Folder 74)
  - 1943 June 12 - 21 (Box 4:, Folder 75)
  - 1943 June 22 (Box 4:, Folder 76)
  - 1943 June 23 - 30 (Box 4:, Folder 77)
  - 1943 July 1 - 14 (Box 4:, Folder 78)
  - 1943 July 15 - 20 (Box 4:, Folder 79)
  - 1943 July 21 - 31 (Box 4:, Folder 80)
  - 1943 August (Box 4:, Folder 81)
  - 1943 September - November 23 (Box 4:, Folder 82)
  - 1943 November 24 - December 29 (Box 4:, Folder 83)
  - 1943 December 30 - 31 (Box 4:, Folder 84)
  - 1944 January 1 - 6 (Box 5:, Folder 85)
  - 1944 January 7 - 20 (Box 5:, Folder 86)
  - 1944 January 21 - February 14 (Box 5:, Folder 87)
  - 1944 February 15 - 29 (Box 5:, Folder 88)
  - 1944 March 1 - 16 (Box 5:, Folder 89)
  - 1944 March 17 - 31 (Box 5:, Folder 90)
  - 1944 April - May 11 (Box 5:, Folder 91)
  - 1944 May 12 - June (Box 5:, Folder 92)
  - 1944 July - September 15 (Box 5:, Folder 93)
  - 1944 September 16 - October (Box 5:, Folder 94)
  - 1944 November - December 20 (Box 5:, Folder 95)
  - 1944 December 21 - 31 (Box 5:, Folder 96)
  - 1945 January 1 - 23 (Box 5:, Folder 97)
  - 1945 January 24 - 31 (Box 5:, Folder 98)
  - 1945 February - March (Box 5:, Folder 99)
  - 1945 April 1 - 12 (Box 5:, Folder 100)
  - 1945 April 13 - 24 (Box 5:, Folder 101)
  - 1945 April 25 - May 15 (Box 5:, Folder 102)
  - 1945 May 16 - June 13 (Box 5:, Folder 103)
  - 1945 June 14 - July 15 (Box 5:, Folder 104)
  - 1945 July 16 - August 8 (Box 5:, Folder 105)
  - 1945 August 9 - September 9 (Box 6:, Folder 106)
  - 1945 September 10 - October 3 (Box 6:, Folder 107)
  - 1945 October 4 - 31 (Box 6:, Folder 108)
  - 1945 November (Box 6:, Folder 109)
  - 1945 December (Box 6:, Folder 110)
  - 1946 January - March 6 (Box 6:, Folder 111)
  - 1946 March 6 - 7 (Box 6:, Folder 112)
  - 1946 March 8 - April 3 (Box 6:, Folder 113)
  - 1946 April 4 - 15 (Box 6:, Folder 114)
  - 1946 April 16 - 30 (Box 6:, Folder 115)
  - 1946 May - June (Box 6:, Folder 116)
  - 1946 July - August (Box 6:, Folder 117)
  - 1946 September - December 10 (Box 6:, Folder 118)
  - 1946 December 11 - 31 (Box 6:, Folder 119)
  - 1947 January (Box 6:, Folder 120)
  - 1947 February - April 2 (Box 6:, Folder 121)
  - 1947 April 3 - 30 (Box 6:, Folder 122)
  - 1947 May 1 - 19 (Box 6:, Folder 123)
  - 1947 May 20 - June 6 (Box 6:, Folder 124)
  - 1947 June 7 - September 18 (Box 6:, Folder 125)
  - 1947 September 19 - October (Box 6:, Folder 126)
  - 1947 November 1 - 21 (Box 6:, Folder 127)
  - 1947 November 22 - December (Box 7, Folder 128)
  - 1948 January - February 12 (Box 7, Folder 129)
  - 1948 February 13 - March (Box 7, Folder 130)
  - 1948 April 1 - 23 (Box 7, Folder 131)
  - 1948 April 24 - May 19 (Box 7, Folder 132)
  - 1948 May 20 - 31 (Box 7, Folder 133)
  - 1948 June - July 27 (Box 7, Folder 134)
  - 1948 July 28 - August 23 (Box 7, Folder 135)
  - 1948 August 24 - September 23 (Box 7, Folder 136)
  - 1948 September 24 - October (Box 7, Folder 137)
  - 1948 November (Box 7, Folder 138)
  - 1949 January (Box 7, Folder 140)
  - 1949 February 1 - 15 (Box 7, Folder 141)
  - 1949 February 16 - April 9 (Box 7, Folder 142)
  - 1949 April 10 - May 9 (Box 7, Folder 143)
  - 1949 May 10 - 26 (Box 7, Folder 144)
  - 1949 May 27 - June 30 (Box 7, Folder 145)
  - 1949 July - August (Box 7, Folder 146)
  - 1949 September - October 24 (Box 7, Folder 147)
  - 1949 October 25 - November 16 (Box 8:, Folder 148)
  - 1949 November 17 - 30 (Box 8:, Folder 149)
  - 1949 December (Box 8:, Folder 150)
  - 1950 January (Box 8:, Folder 151)
  - 1950 February - March (Box 8:, Folder 152)
  - 1950 April (Box 8:, Folder 153)
  - 1950 May (Box 8:, Folder 154)
  - 1950 June (Box 8:, Folder 155)
  - 1950 July (Box 8:, Folder 156)
  - 1950 August (Box 8:, Folder 157)
  - 1950 September - October (Box 8:, Folder 158)
  - 1950 November - December (Box 8:, Folder 159)
  - 1951 January (Box 8:, Folder 160)
  - 1951 February - March (Box 8:, Folder 161)
  - 1951 April - May (Box 8:, Folder 162)
  - 1951 June - August (Box 8:, Folder 163)
  - 1951 September - October (Box 8:, Folder 164)
  - 1951 November (Box 9:, Folder 165)
  - 1951 December (Box 9:, Folder 166)
  - 1952 January (Box 9:, Folder 167)
  - 1952 February - March (Box 9:, Folder 168)
  - 1952 April (Box 9:, Folder 169)
  - 1952 May (Box 9:, Folder 170)
  - 1952 June (Box 9:, Folder 171)
  - 1952 July - August (Box 9:, Folder 172)
  - 1952 September (Box 9:, Folder 173)
  - 1952 November (Box 9:, Folder 174)
  - 1952 December (Box 9:, Folder 175)
  - 1953 January - February (Box 9:, Folder 176)
  - 1953 March (Box 9:, Folder 177)
  - 1953 April (Box 9:, Folder 178)
  - 1953 May - June (Box 10:, Folder 179)
  - 1953 July - August (Box 10:, Folder 180)
  - 1953 September - October (Box 10:, Folder 181)
  - 1953 November - December (Box 10:, Folder 182)
  - 1954 January (Box 10:, Folder 183)
  - 1954 February - March (Box 10:, Folder 184)
  - 1954 April (Box 10:, Folder 185)
  - 1954 May (Box 10:, Folder 186)
  - 1954 June (Box 10:, Folder 187)
  - 1954 July (Box 10:, Folder 188)
  - 1954 August (Box 10:, Folder 189)
  - 1954 September - October (Box 10:, Folder 190)
  - 1954 November - December (Box 10:, Folder 191)
  - 1955 January - February 9 (Box 10:, Folder 192)
  - 1955 February 10 - March (Box 11:, Folder 193)
  - 1955 April - May 13 (Box 11:, Folder 194)
  - 1955 May 14 - 31 (Box 11:, Folder 195)
  - 1955 June (Box 11:, Folder 196)
  - 1955 July - August (Box 11:, Folder 197)
  - 1955 September (Box 11:, Folder 198)
  - 1955 October (Box 11:, Folder 199)
  - 1955 November (Box 11:, Folder 200)
  - 1955 December (Box 11:, Folder 201)
  - 1956 January (Box 11:, Folder 202)
  - 1956 February (Box 11:, Folder 203)
  - 1956 March (Box 11:, Folder 204)
  - 1956 April (Box 12:, Folder 205)
  - 1956 May (Box 12:, Folder 206)
  - 1956 June (Box 12:, Folder 207)
  - 1956 July (Box 12:, Folder 208)
  - 1956 August (Box 12:, Folder 209)
  - 1956 September (Box 12:, Folder 210)
  - 1956 October (Box 12:, Folder 211)
  - 1956 November (Box 12:, Folder 212)
  - 1956 December (Box 12:, Folder 213)
  - 1957 January (Box 12:, Folder 214)
  - 1957 February - March (Box 12:, Folder 215)
  - 1957 April (Box 13:, Folder 216)
  - 1957 May (Box 13:, Folder 217)
  - 1957 June - July (Box 13:, Folder 218)
  - 1957 August - September (Box 13:, Folder 219)
  - 1957 October - December (Box 13:, Folder 220)
  - 1958 January - February (Box 13:, Folder 221)
  - 1958 March (Box 13:, Folder 222)
  - 1958 April - May (Box 13:, Folder 223)
  - 1958 June (Box 13:, Folder 224)
  - 1958 July - September (Box 13:, Folder 225)
  - 1958 October - December (Box 13:, Folder 226)
  - 1959 January - June (Box 13:, Folder 227)
- Series II: Select Correspondence, undated, 1841-1971
  - Bakewell, C.M., 1933 (Box 14:, Folder 228)
  - Barnes, Fuller, 1915-1916 (Box 14:, Folder 229)
  - Barnes, Fuller, 1940-1951 (Box 14:, Folder 230)
  - Betts, Charlotte (postcards to her), undated, 1915-1939 (Box 14:, Folder 231)
  - Betts, Charlotte (postcards to her), 1940-1943 (Box 14:, Folder 232)
  - Cheyne, Pierre, 1921-1941 (Box 14:, Folder 233)
  - Cheyne, Pierre, 1942-1943 (Box 14:, Folder 234)
  - Cheyne, Pierre, 1943-1944 (Box 14:, Folder 235)
  - Cheyne, Pierre, 1944-1945 (Box 14:, Folder 236)
  - Cheyne, Pierre, 1946-1965 (Box 14:, Folder 237)
  - Family correspondence, 1841-1863 (Box 14:, Folder 238)
  - Family correspondence, 1943-1962 (Box 14:, Folder 239)
  - Ferguson, Smith, 1942-1949 (Box 14:, Folder 240)
  - Frederickson, George, 1942-1946 (Box 14:, Folder 241)
  - General Correspondence, undated (Box 14:, Folder 242)
  - General Correspondence, 1871-1929 (Box 14:, Folder 243)
  - General Correspondence, 1930-1939 (Box 14:, Folder 244)
  - General Correspondence, 1940-1949 (Box 15:, Folder 245)
  - General Correspondence, 1950-1959 (Box 15:, Folder 246)
  - General Correspondence, 1961-1971 (Box 15:, Folder 247)
  - Hoover, Herbert, 1937-1959 (Box 15:, Folder 248)
  - Ingraham, Dudley, undated, 1909-1966 (Box 15:, Folder 249)
  - Ingraham, William, 1900-1929 (Box 15:, Folder 250)
  - Omatsu, Yasoji, 1949-1950 (Box 15:, Folder 251)
  - Omatsu, Yasoji, 1951-1966 (Box 15:, Folder 252)
  - Purtell, William, 1957 (Box 15:, Folder 253)
  - Sadlak, Antoni, 1957 (Box 15:, Folder 254)
  - Seymour, George, 1908-1929 (Box 15:, Folder 255)
  - Seymour, George, 1929-1932 (Box 15:, Folder 256)
  - Seymour, George, 1933-1944 (Box 15:, Folder 257)
  - Vermeish, Jean A., 1960-1967 (Box 15:, Folder 258)
  - Walcott, Frederic, 1933 (Box 15:, Folder 259)
  - Whitehead, R.H., undated, 1947-1948 (Box 15:, Folder 260)
  - Yale University Library, undated, 1926-1971 (Box 15:, Folder 261)
- Series III: Personal Correspondence, undated, 1883-1964
  - undated (Box 16:, Folder 262)
  - 1883 August - 1888 May (Box 16:, Folder 263)
  - 1902 July - August (Box 16:, Folder 264)
  - 1903 April - December (Box 16:, Folder 265)
  - 1904 (Box 16:, Folder 266)
  - 1904 April - October 7 (Box 16:, Folder 267)
  - 1904 October - December (Box 16:, Folder 268)
  - 1905 January - March (Box 16:, Folder 269)
  - 1905 (Box 16:, Folder 270)
  - 1905 April - September (Box 16:, Folder 271)
  - 1905 October (Box 16:, Folder 272)
  - 1905 November - December (Box 16:, Folder 273)
  - 1906 January (Box 16:, Folder 274)
  - 1906 February (Box 16:, Folder 275)
  - 1906 March (Box 16:, Folder 276)
  - 1906 April (Box 16:, Folder 277)
  - 1906 May (Box 16:, Folder 278)
  - 1906 June (Box 16:, Folder 279)
  - 1906 October - December (Box 16:, Folder 280)
  - 1907 January (Box 17:, Folder 281)
  - 1907 February - April (Box 17:, Folder 282)
  - 1907 May - June (Box 17:, Folder 283)
  - 1907 August - December (Box 17:, Folder 284)
  - 1908 January - February (Box 17:, Folder 285)
  - 1908 March - April (Box 17:, Folder 286)
  - 1908 May (Box 17:, Folder 287)
  - 1908 June - July (Box 17:, Folder 288)
  - 1908 August - September (Box 17:, Folder 289)
  - 1908 October (Box 17:, Folder 290)
  - 1908 November (Box 17:, Folder 291)
  - 1908 December (Box 17:, Folder 292)
  - 1909 (Box 17:, Folder 293)
  - 1909 January - February (Box 17:, Folder 294)
  - 1909 March - April (Box 17:, Folder 295)
  - 1909 May (Box 17:, Folder 296)
  - 1909 June - July (Box 17:, Folder 297)
  - 1909 August - September (Box 17:, Folder 298)
  - 1909 October (Box 17:, Folder 299)
  - 1909 November - December (Box 17:, Folder 300)
  - 1910 (Box 17:, Folder 301)
  - 1910 January - February (Box 17:, Folder 302)
  - 1910 March - April (Box 17:, Folder 303)
  - 1910 May - June (Box 17:, Folder 304)
  - 1910 July (Box 17:, Folder 305)
  - 1910 August (Box 17:, Folder 306)
  - 1910 September - December (Box 18:, Folder 307)
  - 1911 (Box 18:, Folder 308)
  - 1911 January - March (Box 18:, Folder 309)
  - 1911 May - August (Box 18:, Folder 310)
  - 1912 May - June (Box 18:, Folder 311)
  - 1912 June - July (Box 18:, Folder 312)
  - 1912 August - September (Box 18:, Folder 313)
  - 1912 October - December (Box 18:, Folder 314)
  - 1913 January - March (Box 18:, Folder 315)
  - 1913 April - June (Box 18:, Folder 316)
  - 1913 July - August (Box 18:, Folder 317)
  - 1913 October - December (Box 18:, Folder 318)
  - 1914 (Box 18:, Folder 319)
  - 1914 January - February (Box 18:, Folder 320)
  - 1914 April (Box 18:, Folder 321)
  - 1914 May - June (Box 18:, Folder 322)
  - 1914 August - October (Box 18:, Folder 323)
  - 1914 November - December (Box 18:, Folder 324)
  - 1915 (Box 19:, Folder 325)
  - 1915 January (Box 19:, Folder 326)
  - 1915 February (Box 19:, Folder 327)
  - 1915 March - April (Box 19:, Folder 328)
  - 1915 May (Box 19:, Folder 329)
  - 1915 June - July (Box 19:, Folder 330)
  - 1915 August - September (Box 19:, Folder 331)
  - 1915 October - December (Box 19:, Folder 332)
  - 1916 (Box 19:, Folder 333)
  - 1916 January (Box 19:, Folder 334)
  - 1916 February - April (Box 19:, Folder 335)
  - 1916 May - June (Box 19:, Folder 336)
  - 1916 July (Box 19:, Folder 337)
  - 1916 August - December (Box 19:, Folder 338)
  - 1917 (Box 19:, Folder 339)
  - 1917 January - March (Box 19:, Folder 340)
  - 1917 April - July (Box 19:, Folder 341)
  - 1917 August (Box 19:, Folder 342)
  - 1917 September (Box 19:, Folder 343)
  - 1917 October - December (Box 19:, Folder 344)
  - 1918 (Box 19:, Folder 345)
  - 1918 January - March (Box 19:, Folder 346)
  - 1918 April - June (Box 20:, Folder 347)
  - 1918 July - September (Box 20:, Folder 348)
  - 1918 October - December (Box 20:, Folder 349)
  - 1919 (Box 20:, Folder 350)
  - 1919 February - August (Box 20:, Folder 351)
  - 1919 September - December (Box 20:, Folder 352)
  - 1920-1925 (Box 20:, Folder 353)
  - 1926-1928 (Box 20:, Folder 354)
  - 1934-1939 (Box 20:, Folder 355)
  - 1941-1945 (Box 20:, Folder 356)
  - 1954-1960 (Box 20:, Folder 357)
  - 1960-1964 (Box 20:, Folder 358)
- Series IV: Writings, undated, 1940-1963
  - Autobiography, 1962 (Box 20:, Folder 359)
  - "Connecticut Clockmaking", 1940 (Box 20:, Folder 360)
  - "Clockmaking in Bristol", undated (Box 21:, Folder 361)
  - "E. Ingraham Company", 1942-1962 (Box 21:, Folder 362)
  - "Effects of World Wars on Clock Industry", 1942 (Box 21:, Folder 363)
  - "Four Generations of Ingraham Management", undated
    - 1 - 50 (Box 21:, Folder 364)
    - 1 - 28 (Box 21:, Folder 365)
    - 1 - 24a (Box 21:, Folder 366)
    - 25a - 45a (Box 21:, Folder 367)
    - 51 - 97 (Box 21:, Folder 368)